nationalheraldindia.com 2018-10-04

# Privacy Policy | National Herald

Thank you for visiting the website of www.nationalheraldindia.com (Site) The Privacy Policy is applicable to the website of www.nationalheraldindia.com which is developed, managed and operated by Associated Journals Limited (“Owner”). This privacy statement also does not apply to the website of our partners, affiliates, agents or to any other third parties, even if their websites are linked to the Site. We recommend you review the privacy statements of the other parties with whom you interact. The following terms govern the collection, use and protection of your personal Information by the Site. This Privacy Policy shall be applicable to users who visit the Site. By visiting and/or using the Site you have agreed to the following Privacy Policy.

## Personal Information

Personal Information means and includes all information that can be linked to a specific individual or to identify any individual, such as name, address, mailing address, telephone number, e - mail address, and any and all details that may be requested while any user visits or uses the Site. In addition the Site may collect sensitive personal data or information which (as per the Rules framed under the Information Technology Act 2000) include: 

  * Password
  * Financial information such as Bank account or credit card or debit card or other payment instrument details
  * Physical, physiological and mental health condition
  * Sexual orientation
  * Medical records and history
  * Biometric information
  * Any detail relating to the above clauses as provided to body corporate for providing service
  * Any of the information received under above clauses by body corporate for processing, stored or processed under lawful contract or otherwise: provided that, any information that is freely available or accessible in public domain or furnished under the Right to Information Act, 2005 or any other law for the time being in force shall not be regarded as sensitive personal data or information for the purposes of these rules.

When you browse the Site, the Site may collect information regarding the domain and host from which you access the Internet, the Internet Protocol address of the computer or Internet Service Provider you are using, and anonymous site statistical data. The Site uses cookie and tracking technology depending on the features offered. Personal Information will not be collected via cookies and other tracking technology; however, if you previously provided personally identifiable information, cookies may be tied to such information. Aggregate cookie and tracking information may be shared with third parties. 

We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy, and become familiar with it, but you should know that we do not sell or rent our users' Personal Information to third parties. Please note that we review our Privacy Policy from time to time, and we may make periodic changes to the policy in connection with that review. Therefore, you may wish to bookmark this page and/or periodically review this page to make sure you have the latest version. Regardless of later updates, we will abide by the privacy practices described to you in this Privacy Policy at the time you provided us with your Personal Information. 

### Information we collect from you

When browsing our Site, you are not required to provide any Personal Information unless and until you choose to sign up for one of our e-mail newsletters or other services as is described in the Site from time to time.

### Registration

If you choose to become a member of the Site, you may be required to provide your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address. Wherein if at any time you chose to accept to become a member of the website in addition to the information before stated you may also be required to provide a unique login name, password, and password validation, and a password hint to help you remember your password. This information is collected on the registration form for several reasons including but not limited to:

  * Personal identification
  * To customize the content of our site to strive to meet your specific needs; and/or
  * To make other improvements to our site. In addition, we need your e - mail address to confirm your new member registration. As a Site member you will also occasionally receive updates from us about the Site’ activities in your area, new Site services, and other noteworthy items. However, you may choose at any time to no longer receive these types of e - mail messages. Please see our Opt - Out Policy described below for details. 

### Online Surveys

The Site values opinions and comments from users, so we may conduct online surveys. Participation in these surveys is entirely optional. Typically, the information is aggregated, and used to make improvements to the Site and its services and to develop appealing content, features and promotions for Site users. Survey participants are anonymous unless otherwise stated in the survey. 

### Automatic Logging of Session Data

We may automatically log generic information about your computer's connection to the Internet, which we call "session data", that is anonymous and not linked to any Personal Information. Session data consists of things such as IP address, operating system and type of browser software being used and the activities conducted by the user while on the Site. An IP address is a number that lets computers attached to the internet, such as our web servers, know where to send data back to the user, such as the pages of the Site the user wishes to view. We may collect session data because it helps us analyze such things as what items visitors are likely to click on most, the way visitors are clicking through the Site, how many visitors are surfing to various pages on the Site, how long visitors to the Site are staying and how often they are visiting. It also helps us diagnose problems with our servers and lets us better administer our systems. Although such information does not identify any visitor personally, it is possible to determine from an IP address a visitor's Internet Service Provider (ISP), and the approximate geographic location of his or her point of connectivity. 

### Cookies

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. You should know that cookies are only read by the server that placed them, and are unable to do such things as run programs on your computer, plant viruses or harvest your Personal Information. The use of cookies is very common on the Internet and the Site use of cookies is similar to that of such sites as any other reputable online portal. First and foremost, you can be rest assured that no personally identifiable information ("PII") about you (e.g., name, address, etc.) is gathered or stored in the cookies placed by the Site and, as a result, none can be passed on to any third parties. Cookies allow us to serve you better and more efficiently, and to personalize your experience at our Site. The Site may use cookies to personalize your experience on the Site as these types of cookies allow you to log in without having to type your log - in name each time (only your password is needed). None of this information is passed to any third party, and is used solely by us to provide you with a better user experience on the Site. A cookie may also be placed by our advertising server. Such cookies are used only for purposes of tracking the effectiveness of advertising served by us on our Site and no PII is gathered from you by the use of these cookies, nor is this information shared with any third parties. Similarly, a cookie may be placed by our third - party advertising companies or advertisement providers or servers. These companies may use aggregated statistics about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide information and updates about the happenings on the Site that you may be interested in or any subject of potential interest to you. The information they collect does not include your PII. The third - party advertising companies or advertisement providers may also employ technology that is used to measure the effectiveness of ads. Any such information is anonymous. They may use this anonymous information about your visits to this and other sites in order to provide information and updates about the happenings on the Site that may interests you. No PII is collected during this process. The information is anonymous, and does not link online actions to an identifiable person. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies. Of course, by changing the options on your web browser or using certain software programs, you can control how and whether cookies will be accepted by your browser. The Site supports your right to block any unwanted Internet activity, especially that of unscrupulous websites. However, blocking the Site cookies may disable certain features on the Site, and may make it impossible to use certain services available on the Site. Please note that it is possible to block cookie activity from certain websites while permitting cookies from websites you trust, like www.iamcourage.com Site. 

### Other

From time to time we may add or enhance services available on the Site. To the extent these services are provided, and used by you, we will use the information you provide to facilitate the service requested. For example, if you email us with a question, we will use your email address, name, nature of the question, etc. to respond to your question. We may also store such information to assist us in making the Site the better and easier to use. With whom we may share your Personal Information? 

For making the use of Site effective and resourceful the Site may share your information with vendors, consultants, and other service providers or volunteers who are engaged by or working with us and who need access to such information to carry out their work for us; to report required information to any statutory body at any time as may be required; when we believe in good faith that we are required to do so by law, court order, as requested by other government or law enforcement authority, or in the good faith belief that disclosure is otherwise necessary or advisable including, without limitation, to protect the rights or properties of the Site or any or all of its affiliates, associates, employees, agents or office bearers or when we have reason to believe that disclosing the information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing interference with our rights or properties, whether intentionally or otherwise, or when anyone else could be harmed by such activities.; to enforce or apply this Policy, our Terms of Usage, or our other policies or agreements. 

How can you opt out of from our website and informational updates?

You may "opt out" of receiving text messages, email updates and newsletters by following the instructions in those text messages and emails. Please note that we may still send you other types of emails, such as emails about your use of our Sites, or use information as otherwise described in this Policy, even if you opt out of receiving email updates and newsletters. Changes to information in your account does not affect information provided to others as set forth in this policy.

What safeguards we have in place to protect your Personal Information?

We take reasonable measures to protect your personal information in an effort to prevent loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Please be aware, however, that despite our efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable and no method of data transmission that can be guaranteed against any interception or other type of misuse. To protect the confidentiality of personal information, you must keep your password confidential and not disclose it to any other person. You are responsible for all uses of our web sites by any person using your password. Please advise us immediately if you believe your password has been misused. 

Does this policy apply to third party links on Site?

Our website may contain links to other websites. Any personal information you provide on the linked pages is provided directly to that third party and is subject to that third party's privacy policy. This Policy does not apply to such linked sites, and we are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of these websites or any other sites that are linked to from our Sites. We encourage you to learn about their privacy and security practices and policies before providing them with personal information. This policy is effective as of (date). Any material changes in the way the Site uses Personal Information will be described in future versions of this Privacy Statement. Of course, you may always submit concerns regarding our Privacy Statement or our privacy practices via email to contact@nationalheraldindia.com. Please reference the privacy policy in your subject line. The Site will attempt to respond to all reasonable concerns or inquiries at the earliest.

These terms and conditions are subject to the laws of India and in particular the Information Technology Act 2000 and the Rules framed therein from time to time. Any part of this policy which may be in contravention of or inconsistent with the Act, Rules as mentioned above or any other applicable law will be deemed as invalid and void and shall be deemed as severed from this policy. Also all relevant and appropriate terms and provisions of such Act and Rules and any other applicable law shall be deemed to have been incorporated herein for the purposes of this policy and use by you of the Site. All disputes are subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts at New Delhi. Thank you for using the Site!

#### Contact Us
